(
"ai_sub_version": "3.3.0",
"generated_at": "2026-07-14T00:24:07.190193",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
AZKi 8th Birthday Live
AZKi
AZKi 8th Birthday Live CrossOver 平成 vs 令和 アニソン歌合戦
AZKi 8th Birthday Live CrossOver: Heisei vs. Reiwa Anime Song Battle
IRyS / 音乃瀬奏
IRyS / Kanade Otonose
みんな、こんあずきー！
Hello, everyone! Kon-AZKi!
今日は、AZKi 8thバースデーライブ「CROSSOVER」
Today is the AZKi 8th Birthday Live "CROSSOVER"...
平成・令和 アニソン歌合戦にお越しいただき、ありがとうございます！
...Heisei vs. Reiwa Anisong Song Battle! Thank you so much for coming!
今回は平成赤チームと
This time, we are split into the Heisei Red Team...
令和青チームの2チームに分かれて、アニソンで歌合戦をやっていきます！
...and the Reiwa Blue Team for an Anisong battle!
今回ゲストのみんなも、それぞれのチームに分かれて参戦してくれます！
All of our guests today will also be split into their respective teams!
ハッシュタグは、「#AZKi生誕ライブ2026」こちらこちら！
The hashtag is #AZKiBirthdayLive2026, right here!
で、ぜひですね、赤チームのここが良かったよーとか
So please post about what you liked about the Red Team...
青チームのここが美しかったよーとかですね、たくさんポストお願いします！
...or how beautiful the Blue Team was! Send us lots of posts!
そして、サムネイルにも書いてありますが、新衣装のお披露目と
And as written on the thumbnail, we have a new outfit reveal...
重大告知もあるので、楽しみにしててください！
...and some major announcements, so please look forward to it!
ということで、みんな、盛り上がる準備はいいかー！
With that said, is everyone ready to get hyped?!
おー！
Oh!
それでは、平成・令和 アニソン歌合戦、開幕です！
Well then, let's begin the Heisei vs. Reiwa Anisong Song Battle!
まずは平成赤チーム、IRyS！
First up is the Heisei Red Team, IRyS!
楽曲は、
Her song is...
アニメ『新世紀エヴァンゲリオン』より、すべての始まりとなる一曲、
...from the anime "Neon Genesis Evangelion," the song where it all began,
『残酷な天使のテーゼ』！
"A Cruel Angel's Thesis"!
続いて令和青チーム、音乃瀬奏！
Next up is the Reiwa Blue Team, Otonose Kanade!
楽曲は、
Her song is...
『シン・エヴァンゲリオン劇場版』より、すべてを終わりに導く曲、
...from "Evangelion: 3.0+1.0 Thrice Upon a Time," the song that brings everything to an end,
『One Last Kiss』！
"One Last Kiss"!
時代を超えて交差する二つのメロディー。
Two melodies crossing over time.
2曲続けてどうぞ！
Please enjoy these two songs back-to-back!
残酷な天使のように
Like a cruel angel,
少年よ 神話になれ
young boy, rise to become a legend.
蒼い風がいま 胸のドアを叩いても
Even though clear blue winds beat on the door of my heart,
私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
you just smile, looking straight at me.
そっとふれるもの もとめることに夢中で
Too involved in yearning for something to touch,
運命さえまだ知らない いたいけな瞳
your innocent eyes still know nothing of fate.
だけどいつか気付くでしょう その背中には
But someday you will notice that on your shoulders
遥か未来めざすための 羽根があること
there are wings to guide you to the far future.
残酷な天使のテーゼ 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
A cruel angel's thesis will someday fly high from the window,
ほとばしる熱いパトスで 思い出を裏切るなら
if memories are betrayed by the overflowing, burning pathos.
この宇宙を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
Holding the cosmos in your arms, young boy, shine like a legend.
マリア
Maria
フライ・トゥ・ヘヴン
Fly to heaven
マリア
Maria
ずっと眠ってる 私の愛の揺りかご
Sleeping for so long in the cradle of my love...
あなただけが 夢の使者に呼ばれる朝がくる
The morning will come when only you are called by a messenger of dreams.
細い首筋を 月あかりが映してる
The moonlight reflects your thin neckline.
世界中の時を止めて 閉じ込めたいけど
I want to stop time in the world and lock it away, but...
もしもふたり逢えたことに意味があるなら
If there is meaning in the fact that we met...
私はそう 自由を知るためのバイブル
Then I am, yes, a bible to know freedom.
残酷な天使のテーゼ 悲しみがそしてはじまる
A cruel angel's thesis, and then the sadness begins.
抱きしめた命のかたち その夢に目覚めたとき
The shape of the life you held, when you wake up from that dream...
誰よりも光を放つ 少年よ 神話になれ
Shining brighter than anyone, young boy, become a legend!
人は愛をつむぎながら 歴史をつくる
While people weave love, they create history.
女神なんてなれないまま 私は生きる
Living as I am, unable to become a goddess.
残酷な天使のテーゼ 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
A cruel angel's thesis will soon fly from the window.
ほとばしる熱いパトスで 思い出を裏切るなら
If you betray your memories with overflowing, hot pathos...
この宇宙を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
Embrace the universe and shine, young boy, become a legend!
One Last Kiss
作詞・作曲 宇多田ヒカル
Lyrics & Composition: Hikaru Utada
初めてのルーブルは なんてことはなかったわ
My first time in the Louvre was no big deal.
私だけのモナリザ もうとっくに出会ってたから
My very own Mona Lisa, because I'd already met her long ago.
初めてあなたを見た あの日動き出した歯車
The day I first saw you, the gears started moving.
止められない喪失の予感
An unstoppable premonition of loss.
もういっぱいあるけど
I already have so many, but...
もう一つ増やしましょう
...let's add one more.
(Can you give me one last kiss?)
忘れたくないこと
Things I don't want to forget.
Oh oh oh oh oh...
忘れたくないこと
Things I don't want to forget.
Oh oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you’ll ever know
「写真は苦手なんだ」 でもそんなものはいらないわ
"I'm not good with pictures," but I don't need such things.
あなたが焼きついたまま 私の心のプロジェクター
You're still burnt into my heart's projector.
寂しくないふりしてた まあ、そんなのお互い様か
I pretended I wasn't lonely; well, I guess that makes two of us.
誰かを求めることは すなわち傷つくことだった
To want someone was to be hurt.
Oh, can you give me one last kiss?
燃えるようなキスをしよう
Let's share a fiery kiss.
忘れたくても
Even if I want to forget...
忘れられないほど
...I can't forget.
Oh oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you’ll ever know
Oh oh oh oh...
もう分かっているよ
I already know
この世の終わりでも
Whether it's the end of the world...
年をとっても
...or I grow to be old,
忘れられない人
The one I won't be able to forget
Oh oh oh oh...
忘れられない人
The one I can't forget
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you’ll ever know
忘れられない人
The one I can't forget
Oh oh oh oh...
I love you more than you’ll ever know
吹いていった風の後を
Chasing after a breeze that blew by,
追いかけた眩しい午後
one dazzling afternoon.
AZKi 8th Birthday Live Crossover!
平成赤チーム
Heisei Red Team!
常闇トワ
Tokoyami Towa!
楽曲は アニメ「けいおん！」より
Her song is from the anime "K-ON!"
ガールズバンド旋風を巻き起こしたクールなロックナンバー「Don't say \"lazy\"」
The cool rock number that whipped up a girls' band sensation: "Don't say 'lazy'"!
続いて令和青チーム
Next, the Reiwa Blue Team!
響咲リオナ
Hibiki Riona!
楽曲は アニメ「ぼっち・ざ・ろっく！」より
Her song is from the anime "Bocchi the Rock!"
令和のバンドアニメの代表曲「星座になれたら」
The representative song of Reiwa's band anime: "If I Could Be a Constellation"!
時代を超えて響き渡るガールズバンドの系譜、二曲続けてどうぞ！
The legacy of girls' bands echoing across eras, please enjoy these two songs back-to-back!
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because actually we are crazy
白鳥たちはそう
Swans are like that
見えないとこでバタ足するんです
Working hard underwater without anyone seeing
本能に従順 忠実 翻弄も重々承知
Faithful to instinct, obedient, we are well aware of being manipulated
前途洋々だし...
Our future is bright anyway...
だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
So we take a break once in a while
この目でしっかり見定めて
Look closely with these eyes
行き先地図上マークして
Mark the destination on the map
近道あればそれが王道
If there is a shortcut, it’s the royal road
はしょれる翼もあれば上等
If there are wings to skip steps, that’s great too
ヤバ 爪割れた グルーで補修した
Oops, I broke a nail, repaired it with glue
それだけでなんか達成感
Just that gives me a sense of accomplishment
大事なのは自分 かわいがること
What’s important is to love yourself
自分を愛さなきゃ 他人も愛せない
If you don't love yourself, you can't love others either
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because actually we are crazy
能ある鷹はそう
Talented hawks are like that
見えないとこにピック隠すんです<
Hiding their picks where they can't be seen
想像に一生懸命
Imagining as hard as we can
現実は絶体絶命
The reality is a critical situation
発展途中だし...
We're still a work in progress...
だから...
So...
だから不意にピッチ外れるんです
That's why my pitch suddenly goes flat
その目に映らないだけだって やる気はメーター振り切って
Just because you can't see it, doesn't mean my motivation isn't off the charts
いつでも全力で夢見て その分全力で眠って
I always dream with all my might, and sleep just as hard in return
ヤリ ちょい痩せた 調子づいて喰った
Awesome, I lost a little weight! But then I got carried away and ate too much
それだけでなんで？敗北感
Why does just that make me feel so defeated?
すかさずに目標 下方修正して
Without delay, I quickly lower my goals
柔軟に臨機応変 七変化が勝ち
Adapting flexibly to situations, the quick-change artist wins
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because in reality, I'm crazy
孔雀たちはそう
Peacocks are just like that
ここぞというとき美を魅せるんです
They only show off their beauty at the crucial moment
五臓六腑 渾身 邁進
Pressing forward with all our heart and soul
願望は痩身 麗人 誘惑多発だし...
My desire is to be a slender beauty, but temptations are everywhere...
だからやけに意志砕けちゃうんです
That's why my willpower easily crumbles
ヤバ まさか赤点！？ いや ギリクリア！
Oh no, did I fail the test?! No, I barely passed!
それだけでなんて全能感
Just that is enough to make me feel omnipotent
大事なのは自分 認めてくこと
The important thing is to accept yourself
自分を許さなきゃ 他人も許せない
If you can't forgive yourself, you can't forgive others
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because in reality, I'm crazy
白鳥たちはそう
Swans are just like that
見えないとこでバタ足するんです
They paddle furiously beneath the surface where you can't see
本能に従順 忠実
Obedient and faithful to instinct
翻弄も重々承知
Fully aware of being played with
前途洋々だし...
Since the future is so bright...
だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
That's why I take a break once in a while
星座になれたら
作詞：樋口愛　作曲：岡東央人
If I Could Be a Constellation
Lyrics: Ai Higuchi / Composition: Otoha Okado
もうすぐ時計は6時
Soon the clock will strike six
もうそこに一番星
The first evening star is already shining there
影を踏んで 夜に紛れたくなる帰り道
Stepping on my shadow, wanting to fade into the night on my way home
どんなに探してみても
No matter how hard I search
一つしかない星
There is only one star
何億光年 離れたところからあんなに輝く
Shining so brightly from billions of light-years away
いいな 君は
How nice it must be for you
みんなから愛されて
To be loved by everyone
「いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ」
"No, I have always been all alone"
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could join you and become a constellation
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
A wish made in an instant on a starry night
きらめいて ゆらめいて 震えてるシグナル
Glimmering, swaying, a trembling signal
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could join you and become a constellation
空見上げて 指をさされるような
Looking up at the sky, as if we are being pointed at
眩しくても
...no matter how dazzling I may be.
つないだ線 解かないで
Please, don't break the thread that binds us together.
僕がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzling I may be.
もうすぐ時計は8時
The clock will soon strike eight.
夜空に満天の星
The night sky is filled with stars.
何億光年 離れたところにはもうないかもしれない
They might no longer exist there, hundreds of millions of light-years away.
月が綺麗で 泣きそうになるのは
The moon is so beautiful, and the reason I feel like crying...
いつの日にか 別れが来るから
...is because one day, our parting will come.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation,
彗星みたい 流れるひとりごと
like a comet, a drifting monologue...
消えていく残像は 真夜中のプリズム
The fading afterimage is a midnight prism.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation,
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
if my earnest wish could reach someone,
変われるかな 夜の淵を
could I change? Tracing the edge of the night...
なぞるような こんな僕でも
...even someone like me.
遥か彼方  僕らは出会ってしまった
In the far distance, we crossed paths...
カルマだから 何度も出会ってしまうよ
...perhaps it's karma that we keep meeting again and again.
雲の隙間で
In the space between the clouds.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation,
夜広げて 描こう絵空事を
let's spread the night and paint our dreams.
暗闇を 照らすような
To illuminate the darkness...
満月じゃなくても
...even if we are not a full moon.
だから集まって 星座になりたい
So I want to gather and become a constellation with you,
色とりどりの光 放つような
like emitting a colorful variety of light.
つないだ線 解かないよ
I won't break the thread that binds us together,
君がどんなに眩しくても
no matter how dazzling you may be.
AZKi 8th Birthday Live CrossOver 平成 vs 令和 アニソン歌合戦
AZKi 8th Birthday Live CrossOver: Heisei vs. Reiwa Anisong Battle!
平成赤チーム ロボ子さん
Heisei Red Team: Roboco-san!
楽曲はアニメ『円盤皇女ワるきゅーレ』より ラブコメから生まれた儚い名曲「Agape」
Her song is 'Agape' from 'UFO Princess Valkyrie,' a fleeting masterpiece born from a rom-com!
続いて令和青チーム
Next up, Reiwa Blue Team:
水宮枢
Mizumiya Su!
楽曲は令和版アニメ『うる星やつら』より 夜の街を駆け抜けるダンスチューン「トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ」
Her song is 'Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous' from 'Urusei Yatsura,' a dance tune that races through the city at night!
宇宙から届いた2つのラブソング 2曲続けてどうぞ
Two love songs sent from space. Please enjoy both tracks back-to-back!
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear you.
君がくれる agape
The agape you give me,
力のかぎり dive!
dive with all your might!
みつめる 触れあう その時
The moment we look at each other, the moment we touch,
愛は二人を 試している
love is testing the two of us.
Time is now
この世の果てまで
To the ends of the earth
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear it
君がくれる Agape
The Agape love that you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
Dive with all of your might!
信じる 応える その瞬間
In that moment, believing and responding...
愛が 僕らを ひとつにする
...love is what makes us one.
Time is now
どこまでも生きて
Live on, no matter how far
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear it
君がくれる Agape
The Agape love that you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
Dive with all of your might!
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear it
君がくれる Agape
The Agape love that you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
Dive with all of your might!
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear it
君がくれる Agape
The Agape love that you give me
力のかぎり Dive!
Dive with all of your might!
Would you call me if you need my love?
どこにいたって聞こえる
Wherever you are, I can hear it
君がくれる Agape
The Agape love that you give me
力のかぎり
With all of my might...
Dive!
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
Speed up the signal, it's super electrifying!
あなたにもわすれたいこと
I wonder if you too have things you want to forget,
かなしいこと あるのかしらね
or things that make you feel sad...
識らない映画なのに涙をながすのは
Shedding tears for a movie you don't even know...
ドラマチックが足りていないからよ
...is because you are lacking drama in your life.
そんな愚にも付かないこと
I can't stop thinking about
くだらないこと考えてばかりね
such stupid, trivial things.
雨が上がれば
When the rain stops,
愛もその横顔も
both love and that profile
誰かのものになるのでしょう
will belong to someone else, I suppose.
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部今夜のためよ
All the fake foundation is just for tonight.
なのに一体全体如何して如何して何故何故?
But why on earth, why, why, why?
不安定なカンテラ何処まで行くの
This unstable lantern, how far will it go?
あなた一切合切放り去ってもう
You've abandoned everything already.
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not joking, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって如何にもならないぜ
Even when that time comes, there's nothing we can do.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコり化するだけ
Vague truths only make things melancholic.
あたしをさあ掻っ攫って今テイクオンミー
Come on, snatch me away, take on me now!
はあ ちゃんちゃらおかしな法度ばっかで食指がびくともしないわ
Haa, with nothing but ridiculous rules, my interest isn't even piqued.
実態の無い感情放っておいたって策略なんてありゃあせんのに何故
Even if I leave my formless emotions alone, why is there no strategy?
ああもう懲り懲りよ あたしの渇となる気質も
Ah, I've had enough! Even my thirst-inducing nature,
じっと堪えて取り繕ってはとうとう臨界点
patiently enduring and keeping up appearances, has finally reached its limit.
年がら年中リップサービス鈍感カマしては辟易
Lip service all year round, acting dense, I'm sick of it.
どんがらがっしゃんフィールガールは涙の目にも鬼
The crash-and-burn emotional girl is a demon even with teary eyes.
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいであなたの話は一向に聴き取れない
Now, because of the music in my head, I can't make out a single word of yours.
少しは真当なこと言って
Say something sensible for once.
回り出すターンテーブル ねえ全部忘れさせてよ
The turntable starts to spin, hey, let me forget everything.
だけど一体全体如何して如何して何故何故?
But why on earth, why, why, why?
不安定なカンテラ消えない侭ね
This unstable lantern remains lit, doesn't it?
あなた一口両舌食い違ってもう
You're speaking with a double tongue, we're totally at odds.
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not joking, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって如何にもならないぜ
Even when that time comes, there's nothing we can do.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコり化するだけ
Vague truths only make things melancholic.
あたしを今...
Me, now...
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not joking, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって如何にもならないぜ
Even when that time comes, there's nothing we can do.
不甲斐ないわ 感情なんてランドリーで落とすだけ
How pathetic, emotions can just be washed away in the laundry.
あたしと確かめ合ってイエロー・マジック
Verify it with me, Yellow Magic.
アイアイヤ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Ai-ya-ya, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous!
その時が来たって如何にもならないぜ
Even when that time comes, there's nothing we can do.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコり化するだけ
Vague truths only make things melancholic.
あたしをさあ掻っ攫って今テイクオンミー
Come on, snatch me away, take on me now!
AZKi 8th Birthday Live Crossover!
最後はチームみんなで歌い上げます
Lastly, everyone in the team will sing together!
平成・赤チーム
Heisei Red Team!
アニメ「とある科学の超電磁砲」より今も愛され続けるアニソンの王道「only my railgun」
From the anime 'A Certain Scientific Railgun,' the classic anime song loved to this day, 'only my railgun'!
続いて令和・青チーム
Next up, Reiwa Blue Team!
アニメ「呪術廻戦」より鮮烈でエモーショナルな青春ソング「青のすみか」
From the anime 'Jujutsu Kaisen,' the vivid and emotional youth anthem, 'Where Our Blue Is'!
ステージでぶつかる電撃と呪力。2曲続けてどうぞ！
Electricity and cursed energy clash on stage. Please enjoy both songs in a row!
放て! 心に刻んだ夢を 未来さえ置き去りにして
Fire it! Leave even the future behind, along with the dreams engraved in your heart.
限界など知らない 意味無い!
I know no limits, they're meaningless!
この能力が光散らす その先に遥かな想いを
This power scatters light, projecting distant feelings beyond.
歩いてきた この道を 振り返ることしか
If there is nothing else I can do but look back...
出来ないなら... 今ここで全てを壊せる
...on the path I have walked, I can destroy everything here and now.
暗闇に堕ちる街並み 人はどこまで立ち向かえるの?
As the townscape falls into darkness, how far can people stand against it?
加速するその痛みから 誰かをきっと守れるよ
From this accelerating pain, I can surely protect someone.
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it, right now!
身体中を
Through my entire body...
身体中を 光の速さで
Through my body at the speed of light,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
a certain premonition ran through.
掴め！望むものなら残さず
Seize it! If it's your wish, don't leave anything behind,
輝ける自分らしさで
with your shining individuality.
信じてるよ あの日の誓いを
I believe in the vow made that day.
この瞳に光る涙
Even the tears glittering in these eyes...
それさえも強さになるから
...will become my strength.
立ち止まると 少しだけ 感じる切なさに
When I stand still, I feel a little sadness.
戸惑う事 無いなんて 嘘はつかないよ
I won't lie and say I have no hesitation.
宇宙に舞うコインが描く 放物線が決める運命
The parabola drawn by the coin dancing in the sky decides our fate.
打ち出した答えが今日も 私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer I shot out rushes through my chest again today.
Sparkling!
The shiny lights awake true desire.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 必ず
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it, without fail!
貫いてく 途惑うことなく
I will pierce through without hesitation.
傷ついても 走り続ける
Even if I get hurt, I'll keep running.
狙え！凛と煌く視線は
Aim! That sharp, glittering gaze...
狂い無く闇を切り裂く
...will slice through the darkness without straying.
迷いなんて 吹き飛ばせばいい
All you have to do is blow away any doubts.
この心が叫ぶ限り
As long as this heart of mine screams...
誰ひとり邪魔などさせない
...I won't let anyone get in my way!
儚く舞う 無数の願いは
The countless wishes dancing transiently...
この両手に積もってゆく
...will pile up in both of my hands.
切り裂く闇に見えてくるのは
What becomes visible as I tear through the darkness...
重く深く 切ない記憶
...are heavy, deep, and painful memories.
色褪せてく現実に揺れる
Swaying in a fading reality...
絶望には負けたくない
...I don't want to lose to despair.
私が今 私であること
The fact that I am myself right now...
胸を張って 全て誇れる！
...I'll stick out my chest and be proud of it all!
Looking the blitz loop this planet to search way
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
only my RAILGUN can shoot it, right now!
身体中を 光の速さで
Through my body at the speed of light,
駆け巡った 確かな予感
a certain premonition ran through.
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Release it! The dream engraved in your heart,
未来さえ置き去りにして
leaving even the future behind.
限界など知らない 意味無い！
I know no limits, they have no meaning!
この能力が光散らす
This power will scatter light...
その先に遥かな想いを
...towards those distant feelings ahead.
青のすみか
[Song: Where Our Blue Is]
どこまでも続くような青の季節は
The blue season that seemed to go on forever,
四つ並ぶ眼の前を遮るものは何もない
there was nothing to block our four lined-up eyes.
アスファルト、蝉時雨を反射して
The asphalt reflecting the downpour of cicada cries,
きみという沈黙が聞こえなくなる
the silence that was you becomes unheard.
この日々が色褪せる
These days are fading,
僕と違うきみの匂いを知ってしまっても
even if I've come to know your scent, different from mine.
置き忘れてきた永遠の底に
Left behind at the bottom of eternity...
今でも青が棲んでいる
...even now, the blue still lives on.
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, the blue remains clear.
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayers or words,
近づけるのに、届かなかった
though they drew close, they never reached.
まるで、静かな恋のような
Just like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
amidst the colors of summer running down my cheeks.
きみを呪う言葉がずっと 喉の奥につかえてる
The words to curse you remain stuck in the back of my throat.
「また会えるよね」って 声にならない声
"We'll meet again, right?" — a voiceless voice.
昼下がり、じめつく風の季節は
In the early afternoon, in the humid, windy season,
想い馳せる、まだ何者でもなかった僕らの肖像
I think back to our portraits when we were still nobody.
何もかも分かち合えたはずだった
We were supposed to share everything.
あの日から少しずつ
Since that day, little by little,
きみと違う僕という呪いが肥えていく
the curse of me being different from you has grown.
きみの笑顔の奥の憂いを
The sadness deep within your smile...
見落としたこと、悔やみ尽くして
I deeply regret overlooking it.
徒花と咲いて散っていくきみに
To you who bloomed like a sterile flower and scattered away,
さよなら
goodbye.
今でも青が棲んでいる
Even now, the blue dwells within.
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now, the blue remains clear.
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayers or words,
近づけるのに、届かなかった
even though they came close, they never reached.
まるで、静かな恋のような
Just like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏のような色のなか
within a color like summer streaming down the cheek.
きみを呪う言葉が
The words that curse you
ずっと喉の奥につかえてる
are constantly stuck in the back of my throat.
「また会えるよね」って、声にならない声
"We'll meet again, right?" My voiceless voice says.
無限に膨張する銀河の星の粒のように
Like the grains of stars in an infinitely expanding galaxy,
指の隙間を零れた
they slipped through my fingers.
はい、ということで、ここまで一気にノンストップでお送りしました！
All right, and with that, we've brought you a non-stop performance up to this point!
平成も令和も名曲ばかりでしたね。
There were so many masterpieces from both the Heisei and Reiwa eras.
どうでしたか？ 好きな曲はありましたか？
How was it? Did you have any favorite songs?
そして、みんな、どっちのチームが良かったかな？
And also, everyone, which team did you think was better?
ふふふふ。えっとですね、この...
Hehehe. Well, you see, this...
このね、今、後ろのこのハートのステージね。
This heart stage behind me right now,
はい、こちらのハートに映し出された...
yes, the color projected on this heart...
色で、どっちのチームが勝ったのか決まります！
will determine which team won!
ぜひ、みんなコメントで、どっちが良かったか教えてください！
Everyone, please let me know in the comments which one you liked better!
ええ？「決められない」？
What? "You can't choose"?
いやいや、そこはね、ちょっとね、決めて...あ、すごい。この二色にね、分かれておりますけれども。
No, no, you have to choose... Ah, amazing! It's split into these two colors.
しっかり決めていただかないと！
You really have to make a choice!
はい、今日はね、あの、平成 vs 令和となっております。
Yes, today it is Heisei versus Reiwa.
はい、ということで、勝ったのは平成赤チームか？
All right, so did the Heisei Red Team win,
それとも令和青チームか？
or was it the Reiwa Blue Team?
一体どっちかな？
Which one could it be?
それじゃあ、行くよ！
Here we go!
さあ、結果はこちら！
Now, here is the result!
どっちかな？
Which one is it?
あれ？なんか紫になっちゃったんですけど！
Huh? It turned purple!
紫って、紫ってどっちですか？
What does purple mean? Which one is purple?
うーん、もうこれは、あの、赤チームも良かったし、青チームも良かったということで、
Well, I guess both the Red and Blue Teams were great,
すべてフュージョンして、紫になってしまった！
so they fused together and turned purple!
ということで、いや、みんな、あの、たくさん歌ったし、みんな最高だったってことにね、します！
So, well, everyone sang so much, so let's say everyone was the absolute best!
いや、なんかなんか、みんなのおかげで、
Also, somehow, thanks to everyone...
あ、なんかパワーが、パワーが溜まってきた気がするな！
I feel like power... power is welling up inside me!
よ、気がする！
I really feel it!
ということで、新衣装です！
And with that, here is my new outfit!
本当に全部
Really, everything...
AZKiの魔力になっちゃった
...has turned into AZKi's magic.
見てください。どうですか？
Please take a look. How is it?
尻尾、尻尾も生えてるんです。
A tail, a tail is also growing!
フリフリフリフリ
Wag, wag, wag, wag.
どうですか？
How is it?
はい。ということで今回は、
Yes. So this time...
小悪魔衣装を仕立てていただきました。
...I had a little devil outfit tailored.
どうでしょうか？どうでしょうか？魔力、魔王？
How is it? How is it? Magic? Demon king?
小悪魔です。はい。
I'm a little devil. Yes.
今回ですね、新衣装はこちらの、小悪魔衣装。可愛いでしょ？
My new outfit this time is this little devil outfit. Cute, right?
たくさんスクショも撮ってくださいね。
Please take lots of screenshots too, okay?
ということで、この衣装でね、せっかくなので、
So, since I have this outfit on,
あの曲を歌っていきたいなと思います。
I'd like to sing that song.
もしかしたらね、小悪魔ですから、この姿なら
Maybe, since I'm a little devil, with this appearance,
魔法とかも、使えちゃうんじゃないのかなと。
magic or something... I might even be able to use!
ということで、ではですね、次の曲、聴いてください！
So, please listen to the next song!
召喚！
Summon!
自分の過去に囚われ 迷って
Trapped by my own past and lost within it,
そうじゃないよと言い聞かせて 全てを
telling myself, "that's not how it is," to everything,
自由に操れるかなんて
whether I can freely control it all,
わからないよと空は霞んで 正解はどこ？
saying "I don't know," the sky grows hazy—where is the correct answer?
僕の手のひらに 残る大事なもの
The important thing remaining in the palm of my hand,
忘れない記憶 何度でも
the unforgettable memory, no matter how many times,
君を守り抜くと叫んで
shouting that I will protect you until the very end,
巻き戻しの中 掴んだ愛は そう
the love I grabbed onto amidst the rewinding of time—yes,
離しはしないから
because I will never let it go.
散りばめた想い 今一度きりの願いへ
The scattered thoughts, now toward this one-time-only wish,
次への僕に 託したよ
I have entrusted it to the next version of myself.
いつかの約束 光の道しるべになる
The promise from someday will become a guidepost of light.
誓いをさあ君のため 最後まで
Now, for your sake, I swear an oath until the very end!
涙さえ力に変えてきっと 描いていた望む未来へ
Turning even tears into strength, surely, to the desired future I had envisioned,
繋ぐよ
I will connect it!
想像を超える事態に狂って
Driven mad by a situation that exceeds imagination,
爪をたてては もがき足掻いて 心は
digging in my claws, tossing and turning, struggling, my heart...
人生の過ちをもう何回
just how many times already,
繰り返しては嫌いになって 泣いてても
have I repeated the mistakes of life, growing to hate myself and crying?
君の憧れは いつも輝いてた
Your longing was always shining brightly.
I'll come back
To your future
僕は抗うだろう 運命に
I will resist against fate.
Breaking out
Breaking down
諦めきれないから
Because I haven't given up!
結ばれた意思は 独りきりじゃない強さへ
The bound will is toward a strength that isn't alone,
紡いだ糸を 手繰り寄せ
drawing closer the spun threads.
見つけた瞳は 理想を現実に変える
The eyes I found change the ideal into reality.
世界はそう君のため 最初から
The world is, yes, for your sake, from the very beginning,
胸に抱いた思い出とずっと あの日から続く決意で
with the memories I held in my chest, and always with the resolve that has continued since that day,
飛べるよ
I can fly,
Redo
あずきち生誕祭 まだまだいけますか？
Azukichi's Birthday Festival! Can we go even further?!
盛り上がっていこう！
Let's heat things up!
君がたとえ僕のこと
Even if you forget about me,
忘れても
even if you do,
僕はもう忘れない 誰も傷つけない
I won't forget anymore, I won't hurt anyone.
消えそうな過去を 救い出すための時間よ
Oh time, meant for rescuing the past that seems about to vanish,
ここから始まれ
start from here!
巡りゆく一瞬を 今一度きりの願いへ
The repeating moment, now toward this one-time-only wish,
確かに僕は 託された
certainly, I have been entrusted with it.
いつかの約束 光の道しるべになる
The promise from someday will become a guidepost of light...
誓いをさあ
I make this vow...
君のため
...for you...
最期まで
...until the very end!
涙さえ力に変えてきっと 描いていた望む未来へ
Turning even tears into strength, to the desired future we envisioned...
繋ぐよ
...I will connect us!
わー！
Wow!
ということで、聴いていただいてありがとうございました！
And with that, thank you very much for listening!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
今日は、小悪魔衣装になって、魔法で召喚しちゃいました！
Today, in this little devil outfit, I summoned her with magic!
召喚されちゃいました！こあずき！
I've been summoned! Ko-AZKi!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということでね、皆さんもご存知だと思いますが、アニソン界のエース、
Yes, and as I'm sure you all know, the ace of the anime song world...
鈴木このみさんに異世界転生してもらいました！
...Suzuki Konomi-san has reincarnated into this alternative world!
召喚されましたー！
I have been summoned!
誕生日をね、今日はお祝いしたいなと思って、参りました。
I came here today wanting to celebrate your birthday.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
Thank you!
ということでですね、一緒に歌った曲は、
So, the song we just sang together was...
『Re:ゼロから始める異世界生活』第1期OPテーマ「Redo」でした！
..."Redo," the season 1 opening theme of Re:ZERO -Starting Life in Another World-!
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you like it?
ドキドキしたなー。
My heart was pounding.
いや、私もめっちゃドキドキした。
Me too, my heart was beating so fast!
なんか『Redo』を人と歌ったことがあんまりなくって、
Actually, I haven't really sung "Redo" as a duet before,
えー！
Really?
あんまり怖い顔をして歌ってないか、すごい心配です。
so I was worried if I made a scary face while singing.
貴重な、貴重な経験、ありがとうございます。
Thank you for such a precious, precious experience.
AZKiちと歌えて楽しかった！
It was so fun singing with AZKi-chi!
そう、AZKiちって呼んでくれてるんですよ、みんな！
Yes, she calls me "AZKi-chi," everyone!
AZKiはね、このみんって呼んでるんですけど。
And I call her "Konomin"!
いや、実はね、出会いのキッカケはですね、
Actually, the reason we met is...
もうずっとAZKiは元々大好きなんですけど、
Well, I've always loved Konomin's songs, but...
このみんがね、あの、
...Konomin, you see...
『異世界かるてっと』の、
...for "Isekai Quartet"...
そうそう、『異世界かるてっと３』のエンディングテーマ、
That's right! The ending theme of "Isekai Quartet 3,"
「キミイロボクイロ」のカルテットバージョンを作ることになりまして、
...we were going to make a quartet version of "Kimiiro Bokuiro."
そう！
Yes!
その時に会社の人から、
And at that time, my staff said,
「誰か一人好きな人を召喚できる権利を差し上げます」って、
"We will give you the right to summon one person you like,"
言われて。
and...
「そんな機会あるなら、AZKiちにお願いしてみたい」と。私、ライブも元々観てたんで、
"If there's such a chance, I want to ask AZKi-chi." Since I had already watched your live shows,
えー！いいんですか？
Oh my, really?
いつかコラボしたいなって気持ちがずっとあったので、
...I had always wanted to collaborate with you someday.
そこでラブコールをして、叶いまして。
So I sent a love call and it came true!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
まさかね、そんなことがありまして、そこからコラボ配信とか、
I can't believe it! That's how it started, and from there we did collab streams...
あとAZKiもね、このみんのライブ観に行かせてもらったりとか、
...and I also went to see Konomin's live concerts, and...
あとはね、ラーメンの、
...and then, ramen...
ラーメンの汁をね、そう、飛ばしました。
...we splashed ramen broth, yes!
配信の日にそういう話をしていて、
On the day of a stream, we talked about that,
すぐLINEを交換して、
and we immediately exchanged LINE contact info,
すぐラーメンの汁を飛ばして、
and went to splash ramen broth together! And then...
すぐその後、焼肉にも行って、
...right after that, we also went to Yakiniku,
油を飛ばする！
...splashing grease!
アフタヌーンティーにも行きました。
We also went to afternoon tea.
一応オシャレなことも、そう、したい。
We also wanted to do something fancy.
結構ね、よく会ってるよね、最近。
We've been meeting up quite often recently.
そうなんです、なんと、仲良くさせていただいております。
Yes, we've gotten really close.
濃厚な付き合いで。
A deep relationship!
濃厚な付き合いをさせていただいておりまして、
Yes, we have a very close friendship going on,
なんと今日、ついにバーチャル空間に来てくれました！
...and today, she finally came to the virtual space!
初めてです！ありがとう！
This is my first time! Thank you!
なんて楽しい空間なんだ！
What a fun space this is!
嬉しすぎる！
I'm so incredibly happy!
なんか、この空間は魔法が使えるって聞いたんですけど、本当ですか？
I heard that you can use magic in this space, is that true?
使っちゃいますか？このみんは一体どんな魔法を？
Shall we use it? What kind of magic do you have, Konomin?
私も魔王繋がりで、1つだけ魔法を覚えてきたんですよ！
Well, in connection with the demon king, I've learned just one spell!
なんと！この日のために？
Wow! Especially for today?
これだけ使える。これはでも、みんなと一緒じゃないと完成しない
I can only use this one. But, this spell won't be complete without everyone...
魔法なんで、ぜひAZKiちへのラブを込めて、
...so with all your love for AZKi-chi,
一緒に歌って魔法を完成させてください！
please sing along with me to complete the magic!
せーの！
One, two...
Happy birthday to you,
Happy birthday dear AZKi-chi,
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
Happy birthday to you.
AZKiち、仕上げをお願いします！
AZKi-chi, please do the honors!
仕上げ？はい！ふー！
The honors? Okay! *blows*
このみんは、炎の使い手でした！
Konomin was a fire user!
おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
まさか歌までプレゼントしていただけるなんて、
I can't believe you even gifted me a song.
もう、ここで命尽きても。
I could die happy right here...
ダメですダメです！命尽きちゃダメなんです！
No, no, no! You can't die!
実は、皆さん、今日重大告知と、
Actually, everyone, today we have a major announcement and...
書いてあると思うんですけどね、サムネに
I think it's already written on the thumbnail, though.
二人から重大告知がございます！
We have a major announcement to make!
なんと！二人のオリジナルコラボ楽曲が出ます！
Our original collaboration song is actually coming out!
やったー！嬉しい！いいんですか？
Yay! I'm so happy! Is it really okay?
ということでタイトルは、せーの、最強未来衝動！
So, the title is, on three... Saikyou Mirai Shoudou!
という、なんだか強そうなタイトルですね。強い曲ですね。強い曲です。
That's quite a powerful-sounding title. It's a powerful song. Yes, it is.
ということで、なんと、今日初披露させていただきます！
And today, we're performing it for the absolute first time!
頑張ろう！それでは早速聴いてもらえますか？
Let's do our best! Shall we have you listen to it right away?
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
よいしょ。よいしょ。それでは聴いてください。
Here we go! Well then, please listen to it!
だから just fly to the star
So just fly to the star
もっと wow wow
More, wow wow
世界中で proudy glow
Proudly glow all over the world
存在など歌い切って無い無い
There's no trace of our existence left, none at all
壊れても関係ない
Even if we break, it doesn't matter
そっと触れるよ 生まれたての星へ
I'll gently touch the newborn star
囁きながら 願い重ねた宇宙(そら)
Whispering as our wishes overlap in the sky
ほどけた軌道は 誰も知らない場所へ
The unraveled orbit heads to a place nobody knows
微かな記憶と夢を この声に込めて
Pouring faint memories and dreams into this voice
今を 過去を
The present, the past...
未来を辿る
...tracing the future
一瞬を 一生を
An instant, a lifetime
この手で掴む
I'll grasp it with these hands
超BIG!BANG!
A super BIG BANG!
ただこのまま果てまで
Just like this, to the very end
溶けちゃって
Melting away
切り裂かれたいような衝動
An impulse like wanting to be torn apart
抱かれて 染まって 振り切って
Embraced, dyed, and shaken off completely
まだ
Still...
まだ ほら また星を 締め付ける
...still, look, once again squeezing the stars
君と絡まってみようか
Shall we try getting tangled together?
止まらないよ 最強未来衝動
It won't stop, the ultimate future impulse
ただ
Just...
ただ ただ ただ ただ 剥がれ落ちてく
...just, just, just peeling and falling away
広がって 咲いて 駆け出して 飛んで
Spreading, blooming, running, and flying
君と just fly to the star
With you, just fly to the star
もっと wow wow
More, wow wow
無重力で dreamy show
A dreamy show in zero gravity
運命など待ちきれ無い無い
We can't wait for destiny, not at all
壊れても関係ない
Even if we break, it doesn't matter
そっと祈るよ 幾千年の星へ
I'll gently pray to the star of thousands of years
彷徨いながら 僕ら出会えたんだ
Wandering around, we managed to find each other
燃え尽きる前に 誰も彼も急ぐよ
Before burning out, everyone is rushing
確かな希望と信念を この声に込めて
Pouring certain hope and conviction into this voice
星よ 光れ
Shine, stars!
闇を照らせ
Illuminate the darkness!
歌よ 響け
Resound, song!
遥か彼方へ
To the far reaches...
超BIG!BANG!
...of a super BIG BANG!
引力にさあ 導かれ
Now, guided by gravity
この手を繋いだら それだけでいい
If we hold hands, that's all we need
聞いて！ 鳴り止まない絶唱
Listen! This ceaseless masterpiece
愛して 焦がして 振り切って
Loving, burning, shaking off completely
まだ
Still...
まだ ほら また宇宙(そら)を 駆け巡る
...still, look, soaring through the sky once again
君を狂わせてみようか
Shall we try driven crazy by this?
止まらないで 絶対未来衝動
Don't stop, the absolute future impulse
ただ
Just...
ただ ただ ただ ただ 生まれ落ちてく
...just, just, just being born into the world
そばにいて 触れて 輝いて 消えて
Stay by my side, touch, shine, and fade away
生きることは
To live is...
銀河を旅する story
...a story of traveling through the galaxy
どこまでも走っていく
Running endlessly, wherever it takes us
どこまでも燃やしていく
Burning endlessly, wherever it goes
どこまでも生命がある限り
Endlessly, as long as life remains...
叫べ
Cry out!
伝えたい この淡い衝動
I want to convey this fleeting impulse
伝えたい この熱い衝動
I want to convey this hot impulse
衝動を ゆけ
Go, this impulse!
ここから
From here...
次元を超えていく
...we will go beyond dimensions...
超えていく
...beyond dimensions...
...going beyond!
歌え!この衝動はきっと
Sing! This impulse will surely...
抱かれて染まって振り切って
...be embraced, dyed, and shaken off.
まだ
Yet...
ほら 星を締め付ける
...look, it constricts the stars.
君と絡まってみようか
Shall we intertwine together?
止まらないよ最強未来衝動
It won't stop, the strongest future impulse!
ただ
Just...
...just...
剥がれ落ちていく
...peeling and falling away...
広がって
...spreading...
咲いて
...blooming...
駆け出して
...running out...
飛んで
...and flying!
だから JUST FLY TO THE STAR
So, just fly to the star!
もっと WOW WOW
More, wow wow!
世界中で PROUDY GLOW
Proudly glow all over the world!
存在など歌い切って無い無い
Singing away our existence, there's none,
壊れても関係ない
even if it breaks, it doesn't matter!
はーい
Yay!
ということで、新曲を披露させていただきました！
And with that, we have performed our new song!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
かっこいい曲になりましたね、このみん
It turned out to be a really cool song, didn't it, Konomi-n?
ええ曲
A great song!
ええ曲、ふふふ
A great song, hehe.
ということでですね、最強未来衝動
So, "Strongest Future Impulse"...
本日このあと、7月2日0時からデジタルリリースされます！
...will be digitally released today after this, on July 2nd at midnight!
わーい！
Yay!
ちょっと、せっかくなんで
Since we're here...
この曲、実は、二人ね、二人で作詞を
...we actually wrote the lyrics for this song together!
そうなんですよ
That's right.
いたしました
Yes, we did.
2日間、一緒に缶詰状態になって
For two days, we locked ourselves in a room...
一緒に缶詰になって部屋にね、閉じこもって
...trapped together in a room,
このみんと一緒に、あの、作詞をするという
and I had the very precious experience...
貴重な、大変貴重な経験をさせていただきました
...of writing the lyrics together with Konomi-n.
いや、私も、なんか、すごい楽しかったし
For me too, it was so much fun,
こう、仲も深まったんじゃないかっていう
and I feel like we grew much closer.
そう、仲も深まったんじゃないかって気がしております
Yes, I really feel like we bonded deeper.
嬉しいです。はい、そんな楽曲ですので
I'm so glad. Yes, since it's that kind of song,
ぜひぜひ、隅々まで聴いてほしいなと思います
I really hope you listen to every single corner of it.
お願いします
Please do!
というわけで、今日はね、この世界に来てくれて
Anyway, thank you so much for coming...
ありがとうございました！
...to this world today!
Thank you so much!
どう、どうでしたか？どうでしたか？
How, how was it? How did it feel?
正直言っていい？
Can I be honest?
めっちゃ楽しい！
It's super fun!
もうなんか順応してる
You've already adapted to it!
そうなの、なんかね
I know, right? Somehow...
あの、なんでも、炎とか出せちゃうんだって
...I can even shoot flames or anything here!
そう、炎も出せちゃうし、最高！
Yes, you can even shoot flames! It's the best!
え、ちょっとさ、最後にさ、二人でこのハートマークを作りませんか？
Hey, why don't we make this heart shape together at the end?
やりたい！
I want to!
じゃあ、いくよ。せーの
Okay, here we go. One, two...
はい！
Ta-da!
いいんじゃないでしょうか！
I think that's perfect!
いいよね！みんな撮れた？スクショもよろしくお願いしますね
Nice! Did everyone get it? Please take screenshots!
はい
Yes!
ということで、このみんと一緒にハートを作ったということで
So, now that we've made a heart together,
最後に、このみんから告知などありますか？ぜひ
to wrap up, do you have any announcements, Konomi-n?
はい！
Yes!
えっと、まず7月11日にアニサマ！
First, on July 11th, Anisama!
夏のアニメの祭典が行われます！
The summer anime festival will be held!
そちらに出ます！
I will be performing there!
すごい！すごい！すごい！
Awesome! That's great!
フェスモードな感じで、アニソンですよね
In full festival mode, singing anime songs!
そう、あちちな、あちちな歌で炎をばんばん出せたらいいなと
Yes, with some hot, passionate songs, I hope to shoot lots of flames!
ここでも、現実でも炎を出してくれます
She'll shoot flames there too, just like here.
お願いします
Please look forward to it!
あとは、私、あのライブが決まってまして
Also, I have a live concert coming up!
11月7日土曜日に東京SGCホールにて
On Saturday, November 7th, at Tokyo SGC Hall...
アニソンコレクションプラス、アニソンだけを歌うライブをやります！
...I will perform 'Anisong Collection Plus', a live concert dedicated solely to anime songs!
なんですって！
No way!
そう、だから今日あずきちゃんが、あずきちがアニソンずっと歌ってて
So today, seeing AZKi-chan singing anime songs the whole time...
そう、今日はアニソンをテーマにしたライブとなっております
Yes, today's live is themed around anime songs.
「めっちゃ楽しいじゃん」って思いながら
...I kept thinking, "This is so much fun!"
私もそんな1日を過ごそうかなと思ってます
And I plan to spend my day like that too.
応援してます！
I'm rooting for you!
あの、代表曲ばっかり流れるそんな
It will be packed with nothing but major hit songs...
そんな、行かなきゃ
...so I absolutely have to go!
ぜひ来てほしい
I'd love for you to come!
行かなきゃ。ぜひぜひ
I must go. Absolutely!
ということで、ぜひ詳しくはアカウントをチェックしていただいて
So please check my social media account for more details...
一緒にアニソンまみれの1日過ごしましょう。よろしくお願いします
...and let's spend a day covered in anime songs together. Thank you!
行きたい！
I want to go!
はい、ということで
All right, then!
非常に残念なんですが
It's extremely unfortunate...
そろそろこのみんを元の世界に戻さないと、アニサマも
...but it's time to send Konomi-n back, or she'll miss Anisama...
名残惜しい！アニソンコレクションもできないので
...and her Anisong Collection! We don't want that.
またご飯行こう
Let's go grab food again!
またご飯行こう、ふふふ
Let's go grab food again, hehe!
ご飯行こうで
Let's grab food!
行こう、行こう！やった
Let's go, let's go! Yay!
じゃあちょっとね、魔法を使ってこのみんを元の世界に戻したいと思います
So, I will use some magic to send Konomi-n back to her original world.
今日はありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for today!
ありがとうございました！おめでとう！
Thank you so much! Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あ、消えちゃった
Ah, she's gone.
はい、ということでですね、サプライズスペシャルゲスト
Yes, and with that, our surprise special guest...
鈴木このみさんに来ていただきました！
...Suzuki Konomi-san joined us!
え、今日のライブ、いかがでしたでしょうか？
So, how did you like today's live show?
本当にね、内容盛りだくさんで。そうだ、このね、新しい
It's really packed with content! That's right, about this new...
小悪魔な衣装のことをあんまり話せなかったので
...little devil outfit, I couldn't talk much about it,
この後、メン限でゆっくり見てもらえたらと思います。
so I hope you can take a slow look at it during the member-only stream afterwards.
実は、いろんなアクセサリーや、サブがあります！ということで
Actually, there are various accessories and variations! So...
ぜひメン限もよろしくお願いします！
...please check out the member-only stream too!
そして、皆様！
And, everyone!
最後に、AZKiから
Lastly, from AZKi...
みんなに嬉しいお知らせです！
...some exciting news for all of you!
こちらをどうぞ！
Here it is, please take a look!
傷ついた感情も 連れて行くから
Because I'll take even my hurt feelings with me...
そっと響く鐘が 新しい未来を感じてる
...the softly echoing bell is feeling a new future.
怖がったって進むしかないでしょ どこまでも
Even if I'm scared, I have no choice but to move forward, no matter how far.
届けこの祈りよ
Reach out, my prayer...
光となれ
...and become the light!
もっと もっと
More, more...
少しずつでもいい 優しい答えを
...even if it's little by little, a gentle answer...
もっと もっと
...more, more...
...more, more!
お待たせしました！
Thank you for waiting!
AZKiソロライブ2025『Departure』Blu-ray発売決定！
AZKi Solo Live 2025 'Departure' Blu-ray release confirmed!
開拓者のみんなと紡いだあのステージが、何度でも見返せます！
You can rewatch that stage we created with all the Pioneers as many times as you want!
本日より、受注受付が開始です！
Accepting orders starting today!
続いて、告知二つ目！
Next, the second announcement!
AZKiの歴史を彩る、CD二作品の再販が本日7月1日より全国流通スタート！
The reissue of two CDs coloring AZKi's history starts national distribution today, July 1st!
対象タイトルは、『Without U』と『Re:Creating world』です！
The target titles are 'Without U' and 'Re:Creating world'!
最後、告知三つ目！
Lastly, the third announcement!
AZKi誕生日記念2026グッズ情報！
AZKi Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise info!
今回はお披露目された小悪魔衣装にちなんだグッズが盛りだくさんです！
This time, there is plenty of merchandise themed after the revealed little devil outfit!
イラストは、信澤収先生に描いていただきました！ありがとうございます。
The illustrations were drawn by Nobusawa Osamu-sensei! Thank you very much.
それでは、詳細を見ていきましょう！
Now, let's look at the details!
まずは、こちら！
First is this!
二層アクリルパネル！
Double-layered acrylic panel!
小悪魔衣装のキービジュアルをアクリルパネルにしました。
The key visual of the little devil outfit is made into an acrylic panel.
二層になっているので、立体的に見えます。
Since it has two layers, it looks three-dimensional.
ステンドグラスの神秘的な美しさと、小悪魔衣装が見せるギャップを楽しんでください。
Please enjoy the gap between the stained glass's mysterious beauty and the little devil outfit.
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
ランダムラバーキーホルダー！
Random rubber keychain!
この後のメン限でも詳しく見せるんですけど、
I'll show it in detail during the member-only stream later, but...
今回の新衣装、実はバリエーションがいっぱいあるので、ラバーキーホルダーにしてもらいました！
...this new outfit actually has many variations, so we turned them into rubber keychains!
君のお気に入りは、どのAZKiかな？
Which AZKi is your favorite?
イラストは、ねとら先生に描いていただきました！
The illustrations were drawn by Netora-sensei!
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
Plushie keychain!
こちらも、小悪魔衣装バージョンとなってます。
This one is also the little devil outfit version.
使い魔みたいな茶目っ気のある表情になっているので、ぜひ相棒として連れ歩いてください！
It has a playful, familiar-like expression, so please take it with you as your partner!
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
おそろいブレスレット！
Matching bracelet!
小悪魔衣装をモチーフにしたデザインのブレスレットです。
A bracelet designed with the little devil outfit as a motif.
日常の中でさりげなく「推し」を身にまとえるのはもちろん、
Not only can you casually wear your 'favorite' in daily life, but...
普段アクセサリーをつけない方には、新衣装の再現コレクションとしてもおすすめのグッズです！
...for those who don't usually wear accessories, it's also highly recommended as a replica collection of the new outfit!
続いては、こちら！
Next is this!
ASMRボイス！
ASMR voice!
ボイスタイトルは『小悪魔チャーミング』。
The voice title is 'Little Devil Charming'.
AZKiが小悪魔っぽく魔法をかけちゃう、
It's an ASMR voice of a 'what if' story...
そんなもしものお話のASMRボイスです。
...where AZKi casts a spell like a little devil.
そして、フルセット購入特典もございます！
And there's also a full-set purchase bonus!
信澤収先生イラストの、AZKiのタロット風カードと、
An AZKi tarot-style card illustrated by Nobusawa Osamu-sensei...
特典ASMRボイスです。
...and a bonus ASMR voice.
数量限定バージョンは、直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りです！
The limited edition version includes a hand-signed autograph & foil-stamped printed message!
通常バージョンは、箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りです！
The regular version includes a foil-stamped printed autograph & message!
ということで、以上、嬉しいお知らせでした！
And that's all for the exciting news!
この後は、メン限でアンコールライブ！
After this, we have the encore live in the member-only stream!
まだメン限に入っていない方も、まだ間に合うので、ぜひ入ってみてください！
If you haven't joined the membership yet, there's still time, so please join us!
実は、今回の新衣装、
Actually, with this new outfit...
みんなにまだ見せていない、あんな姿や、こんな姿があるので、見に来てくれたら嬉しいです！
...there are looks I haven't shown everyone yet, so I'd be happy if you came to see!
誕生日、たくさんお祝いしてくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you so much for all the birthday wishes!
ライブも見てくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you for watching the live stream too!
それじゃあ、この後メン限で会おうね！
Well then, see you in the member-only stream afterwards!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
AZKi 8th Birthday Live CrossOver
〜平成 vs 令和 アニソン歌合戦〜 (新衣装お披露目 / 重大告知あり)
~Heisei vs. Reiwa Anime Song Battle~ (New Costume Reveal / Major Announcement)